Zeeshan Ashraf

Software Developer

Phone: 03025185776

Email: zeeshan.arcit92@gmail.com

Address: Street #2, Dhok haidery, Koral Chowk, Islamabad, Islamabad Capital Territory, Pakistan, 46000

Software engineer with thorough hands-on experience in development phase and testing phase. Supportive and enthusiastic team player dedicated to strengthening processes and efficiently resolving project issues. Willing to take ownership of core components.

Work History

2021-05 - Present

Back-End Developer at Jovi Technologies

 Working as a backend developer involved in many system process and architectural design and development of some key features.

Technologies: .Net Core (C#, Web API, Entity Framework (Code first)), MS SQL

2018-12 - 2021-04

Software Developer at Digital Ivy, I-9/2 Islamabad

- Worked closely on ERP with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust business solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance. Also worked individually on different projects with the same motivation.
- Human resources system integrated with current ERP solution, features having leave management, payroll, live attendance (with manual and fingerprint), Employee promotions and suspensions, Loan management and some other essential features.
- Development and designing of their different processes and integrating it with the current system.
- Team coordination and meetings for better understanding of system requirements.
- System deployment handling.
- Optimization of the system for better performance

Technologies: .Net (C#, MVC, Web API, Entity Framework (Code first)), Angular, JQuery, JavaScript, CSS, bootstrap, MS SQL

2016-11 - 2018-11

Software Developer at Erpin technologies islamabad

- Designed, implemented and maintained ERP web applications and window applications for different clients.
- Development and revamping of system UI.
- SMS application integrated with the main solution for sending messages to customers.
- Being a part of system process and architecture designing.
- Problem solving and finding issues to make the system efficient.

Qualification

2012 – 2016 Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Federal Urdu University Islamabad

2010 – 2012 FSC pre-engineering

Punjab College

2010 Matric

Siddeeq public school

Skills

Motivated and hardworking

- Able to work under pressure
- Adaptive to new environment and technologies
- Problem Resolution
- Process Improvement
- Architecture design
- Technical analysis
- UI design

Technologies:

- .Net (C#, Web Api, Entity Framework, Core)
- Angular, JQuery, JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- SQL

Languages

- English
- Urdu

Interests

- Software Development
- Software Architecture
- Bikes
- Tourism